Guide to the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association records, circa 1800-2022 MS2027
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association records
circa 1800-2022
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association
MS2027
56 Linear Feet
Collection contains correspondence, obituaries, reports, photographs, slides, newsletters, booklets, membership data, programs, brochures, minutes, and by-laws. The material dates from the early 1800s to 2021 with the bulk of the material falling between 1954-2013. This material relates to the history of both the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal and the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association.
Acquisition Information
In 1991 the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canal Association donated its papers to Gelman Library. There have been subsequent donations from that time.
Historical Note
According to its corporate charter and bylaws the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association continues its mission of protecting, preserving and promoting the assets of the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Historic Park. The Canal National Historical Park is administered by the National Park Service. Surrounded by more than 20,000 acres of parkland, the canal is 185 miles long and follows the Potomac River. It begins in the Georgetown section of Washington, D.C. and ends in Cumberland, Maryland. Located in Georgetown, the Foundry Mall center is one of five visitors' centers and offers visitors' mule-drawn boat rides along the canal route. Historic sites along the canal include the Harpers Ferry National Historical Park, the Antietam Battlefield, Fort Frederick State Park, and Fort Tonoloway. The Chesapeake & Ohio Canal National Historical Park is open for hiking, biking, camping, canoeing, boating, picnicking, ice skating and rock climbing.
In 1950 as the canal ceased to be commercially useful, plans were made to bulldoze it and pave a super-highway into Maryland's mountains. Supreme Court Justice William O. Douglas was one of the few people who realized the historical, cultural, geological and botanical significance of the Chesapeake & Ohio. He challenged two Washington Post editors to walk the length of the 184-mile Chesapeake & Ohio with him and then decide if it the canal and its structures should be destroyed.
The reporters, along with 32 others, took the eight-day hike in March of 1954 and then joined Douglas in the effort to save the canal. That effort resulted in the formation of the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association and, 17 years later, the passage of legislation that created the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal National Historical Park, now one of the major areas of tourism in the National Park System. As one of his last official acts in office in 1961, President Eisenhower proclaimed the canal a national monument. In the mid 1970s the canal and towpath were dedicated to Justice Douplas in honor of his singular contribution to the nation's park system.
The Canal Association was first organized as an advocacy group to preserve the canal. Today, the Association focuses more on recreational and social activities, providing a range of programs and activities encouraging use of the park. The hike that Justice Douglas started in 1954 is now an annual event known as the Heritage hikes, and programs such as the Levels Walkers offer continual detailed reports of the physical status of the park.
Chesapeake & Ohio Canal In 1784, George Washington founded the Potomac Canal Company to begin building a canal along the Potomac River in Virginia. This company was incorporated as the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Company in 1824. On July 4, 1828, at Little Falls, Maryland, President John Quincy Adams shoveled out the first piece of land that signaled the $11 million dollar construction of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal. This project would join the canals that existed separately in Virginia and Maryland.
On October 10, 1850, the canal opened, creating a continuous artificial waterway along the Potomac River. However, increased railroad routes quickly diminished the effectiveness of the canal as a major commercial route and by 1925, the Chesapeake & Ohio canal was no longer used commercially. The Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Co. (B&O) then bought the land once owned by the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Company. In 1938, the B&O Railroad Co. sold the entire canal to the U.S. government for $2 million. The canal was placed under the supervision of the Nationals Park Service in 1950.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains correspondence, obituaries, reports, photographs, slides, newsletters, booklets, membership data, programs, brochures, minutes, and by-laws. The material dates from the early 1800s to 2022 with the bulk of the material falling between 1954-2013. This material relates to the history of both the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal and the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association.
Collection Organization
Organized into six series: Images, Administration files, Audio-visual materials, Personal papers, Records of past presidents Ken Rollins, Rachael Stewart and Carl Linden, and Newsletter: Along the Towpath.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Black-and-white slides; Audiocassettes; Potomac River; Videotapes; Color slides; Cumberland (Md.); Photographs; Chesapeake and Ohio Canal (Md. and Washington, D.C.); Georgetown (Washington, D.C.); Douglas, William O. (William Orville); Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David)
- Images, Circa 1960-Circa 1998; MS2027 Series 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of photographs, negatives, transparencies, and slides. These images are all related to activities related to the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal.
  - Canal Barges-John Quincy Adams, Canal Clipper II, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    General note
    Text on photograph: "Canal Boat"
  - Canal Barges-John Quincy Adams, Canal Clipper II, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Canal barges-John Quincy Adams, Canal Clipper II, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Bridge-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Text on photograph: "May91L"
  - Bridge-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Text on photograph: "May 91L"
  - Bridge-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Text on photograph: "9 5 '93"
  - Bridge-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Bridge-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Text on photograph: "1970 11 498"
  - Bridge-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Text on photograph: "1953 11 498"
  - Buildings-Great Falls Tavern, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    Text on photograph: "E. N. Holway"
  - Buildings-Great Falls Tavern, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - The Cushwa Warehouse, Williamsport, 1992 February 02 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    Text on photograph: "Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association P.O. Box 366 Glen Echo, Maryland 20812-0366 Cushwa Blg Williamsport Mr & Mrs David M. Johnson 9211 Wadsworth Drive Bethesda, MD 20817"
  - The Cushwa Warehouse, Williamsport, 1994 March 05 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    Text on photograph: "The Cushwa Warehouse in Williamsport, on March 5, 1994"
  - Cumberland Train Station, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Buildings-unknown locations, undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
    Text on photograph: "5 5 '93"
  - Buildings-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
    Text o photograph: "5 5 '93"
  - Building-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
    Text on photograph: "3 081 4591/13"
  - Building and bridge-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Buildings, bridge and canal-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Building, bridge and canal-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Barge in Canal Lock-unknown location, 1994 June 14 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    Text on photograph: "Water entering into lock as seen from bay in lock 5/14/94"
  - Barge in Canal Lock-unknown locations, 1994 May 14 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    Text on photograph: "More water entering lock 20 Chesapeake & Ohio new member Barge trip 5/14/94"
  - Canal Lock-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Canal Lock-unknown location, undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1986 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    Text on photograph: "Stephen & Ruby"
  - Tunnel-unknown location, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    Text on photograph: "8 5'93"
  - Event-Birdwalk, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    Text on photograph: "Birders White & Fury on Pal Schwadle & Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Assn Bird walk"
  - Event-Boy Scouts at canal, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Event-Boy Scouts at canal, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Event-Boy Scouts at canal, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Event-Boy Scouts at canal, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Event-Boy Scouts at canal, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Event-Boy Scouts at canal, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Event-Boy Scouts at canal, Circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    Text on photograph: "July 17, 1993 - Brunswick to Monocacy Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoeists"
    Duplicate photograph found in folder for canoe trip from September 11-12, 1993 from Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans.
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoer-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    Text on photograph: "7/17/93 Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers"
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    Text on photograph: "7/17/93 Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Assn Canoers"
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    Text with photograph: "7/17/93 Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Assn Canoers"
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoer-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    Text with photograph: "7/17/93 Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers"
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Brunswick to Monocacy, 1993 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    Text on photograph: "7/17/1993 Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Assn Canoers"
    Duplicate photograph found in folder for canoe trip from Sept. 11 -12, 1993 from Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    Text on photograph: "9/11-12/1993 Canoeists make ready PG 18 Canoeists make prep to leave Stickpile Hill Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association P.O. Box 366 Glen Echo Maryland 20812-0366"
  - Canal trip participants-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 47)
    Text on photograph: "9/11-12/1993 Participants Pg 18 Paw Paw Bends Canoe Trip Participants Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association P.O. Box 366 Glen Echo, Maryland 20812-0366"
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association Dinner, 1993 September 11-1993 June 12 (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Associaton Dinner, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Campers and canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Campers and canoers-Paw Paw Bemds to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 51)
    Text on the photograph: "Sept 11-12th 1993 Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Assn - Canoers & Campers Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans"
  - People and Llamas, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - People and Llamas, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 53)
  - People and Llamas, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - People and Llamas, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 55)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Campers and canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 56)
    Text on photograph: "Sept 11-12th 1993 Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Assn - Canoes & Campers Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans"
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 57)
    Text on photograph: "9/11-12/1993"
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 58)
    Text on the photograph: "9/11-12/1993"
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canla Canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 59)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Campers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 60)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 61)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 62)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Canoers-Paw Paw Bends to Little Orleans, 1993 September 11-1993 September 12 (Box 25, Folder 63)
  - Canoeing along the canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 64)
    Text on photograph: "7 853"
  - Canoeing along the canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 65)
  - Canoeing along the canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 66)
  - Canoeing along the canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 67)
    Text on photograph: "3 374 #13 crop as shown 17a 23x17 46% Ductone (Green & Black)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Monocacy Aqueduct, 1992 October 21 (Box 25, Folder 68)
    Text with photograph: "Photos taken by Orrin Long. 1. Wide-Angle, Panoramic Shots Of Monocacy Aque. Were Taken During Intl Conf On Hist Canals Field Trip, 21 Oct 1992.
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-filed trip at Monocacy Aqueduct, 1992 October 21 (Box 25, Folder 69)
    Text with photograph: " Photos Taken By Orrin Long. 1. Wide-Angle, Panoramic Shots Of Monocacy Aque. Were Taken During Intl Conf on Hist Canals Field Trip. 21 Oct 1992."
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Monocacy Aqueduct, 1992 October 21 (Box 25, Folder 70)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Monocacy Aqueduct, 1992 October 21 (Box 25, Folder 71)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Monocacy Aqueduct, 1992 October 21 (Box 25, Folder 72)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Monocacy Acqueduct, 1992 October 21 (Box 25, Folder 73)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 74)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada Plaque, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 75)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 76)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 77)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 78)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 79)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-Bagpiper, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 80)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 81)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 82)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 83)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 84)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 85)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 86)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 87)
    Photographers finger in top left corner of photograph.
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 88)
    Photographer's finger(?) on left side of photograph.
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 89)
  - Petroglyphs, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 90)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1999 September (Box 25, Folder 91)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 92)
  - Petroglyphs, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 93)
  - Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 94)
  - Boat at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 95)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 96)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 97)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 98)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 99)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 100)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 101)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 102)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 103)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 104)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 105)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 106)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 107)
  - Marine railway at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 108)
    Photograph of Big Chute Marine Railway
  - Marine railway at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 109)
    Photograph of the Big Chute marine railway.
  - Marine railway at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 110)
  - International Conference on Historic Canals-field trip at Severn Canal, Canada, 1994 September (Box 25, Folder 111)
  - People-Reunion dinner, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 112)
    Images of Walter and Elizabeth Boardman and others.
  - People-Reunion dinner, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 113)
    Esther Korns and unknown.
  - People-Reunion dinner, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 114)
    Images of unknown, George Haig, unknown, Congressman Gude and Grant Conway.
  - People-Reunion dinner, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 115)
    Image of unknown.
  - Speaker at Dinner-La Vale, MD, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 116)
    Unknown speaker.
  - Dinner-The Winchhouse, June 4th, Circa 1994 June 04 (Box 25, Folder 117)
    Text on photograph: "Steak dinner at the Winch House, Dam No. 4 Day #20, June 4, LR John R. Thompson, John Mylar, "Doc", and DNR officer Jon Carpenter."
  - Exhibit booth at Brunswick Festival, 1993 October 13 (Box 25, Folder 118)
    Text on photograph: "Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Exhibit at Brunswick Days 10/03/1993"
  - Exhibit booth at Williamsport, MD Canal Days, 1993 August (Box 25, Folder 119)
    Text with photograph: "V Photo - Wiilliamsport 3 x 5 color - Hal & Jane Larsen, Peggy & Nick Weber, Canal Days, 8-1993"
    Text on photograph:: "Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association P.O. Box 366 Glen Echo, Maryland 20812-0366"
  - Cumberland Festival, Circa 1992 (Box 25, Folder 120)
    Text on photograph: "Park Superintendent Tom Hobbs and Mrs. Hobbs at the Association booth at the Cumberland Festival.
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 121)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 122)
  - Railroad tracks-Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 123)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 124)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 125)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 126)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 127)
  - Dairy store-Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 128)
    High's Dairy Store
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 129)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 130)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 131)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 132)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 133)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 134)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 135)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 136)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 137)
  - Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 138)
  - Photographs, Event-Flooding at Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 139)
  - Flood damage at Monocacy Aqueduct, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 140)
    Text on photograph: "Damage from heavy May rains at Mononacy Aqueduct Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Nat Hist Park 6/19/88 mi 42.19 E.N. Holway"
  - Damaged Automobile-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 141)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 142)
    Text on photograph: "Cars which went under Culvert & into river from Glen Echo Parking Lot as a result of flash flood 6/7/89"
  - Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 143)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 144)
  - Damaged automobile-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 145)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 146)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 147)
  - Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 148)
  - Damaged Automobile-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 149)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 150)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 151)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 152)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 153)
  - Damaged Automobiles-Flooding at Glen Echo, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 154)
  - Silt dumping along canal at Cardrock, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 155)
    Text on photograph: "March 11 Cardrock area silt dump E. N. Holway"
  - Silt dumping along canal at Cardrock, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 156)
    Text on photograph: "Dumped sludge below prison[?] bridge & between river & towpath March 11 1989 below mi 9.92"
  - Silt dumping along canal at Cardrock, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 157)
    Text on photograph: "Silt dump site March 11 1989 Cardrock E. E. Holway"
  - Silt dumping along canal at Cardrock, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 158)
    Text on photograph: "Silt dump site below Cardrock March 11, 1989 E. N. Holway"
  - Hike from Sideling Hill Creek to Hancock, Circa 1959 (Box 25, Folder 159)